Guide to the Stanford University, Wilbur Hall, Records SC1290
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Wilbur Hall, Records
2005-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Wilbur Hall
SC1290
25 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
Content Description
Collection consists of Trancos theme banners and t-shirts, as well as other dorm records dating from 2005-2016.
Biographical / Historical
Wilbur Hall is a residence complex on the Stanford University campus, consisting of eight named houses. Wilbur Hall is named for Ray Lyman Wilbur, a Stanford alumnus, who served as dean of the Stanford School of Medicine, third Stanford president (1916-1943), and chancellor. As with Stern Hall, Wilbur was built following World War II and moved away from the arches and intricacies that characterized the rest of Stanford campus. Each house in Wilbur is named for a Spanish word. Though originally designed as an all-men’s residence, the complex has been co-ed for several decades.
Excerpted from https://rde.stanford.edu/studenthousing/wilbur-hall
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Administrative transfer, 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Dormitories -- California -- Stanford.; Stanford University. Wilbur Hall
- Trancos records, Accession ARCH-2016-118
  Biographical / Historical
  Trancos is a sophomore priority, co-educational house.
  - Dorm flag for academic year, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
  - Description of Dormitory Themes, 2006-20146 (Box 1)
  - Trancos Staff Handbook, 2015-9-4 (Box 1)
  - Trancos Yearbook, 2014-2015 (Box 1)
  - Dorm flag for academic year, 2010-2011 (Box 2)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: TranCoaster, 2009-2010 (Box 3)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: Trancasablanca, 2015-2016 (Box 4)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: TrancOlympics, 2012-2013 (Box 5)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: TrancOz, 2013-2014 (Box 6)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: Oceans Eleven, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: Ghostbusters, 2007-2008 (Box 8)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: Trancosmos, 2014-2015 (Box 9)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: Trancasablanca, 2008-2009 (Box 10)
  - Dorm flag for academic year: TranCoral Reef, 2011-2012 (Box 11)
  - Sweater, undated (Box 12)
  - T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - TrancOz T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - Trancoral Reef T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - Trancoaster T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - TrancOlympics T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - T-shirt, undated (Box 12)
  - Trancasablanca T-shirt, undated (Box 12)